Guide to the William C. Lynch Dennis Brain Collection ARS.0138
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Vinyl discs, circa 1926-1957; 55 vinyl discs 54 12" vinyl discs; 1 10" vinyl disc
  - Delius, 1947-1954; 1 12" vinyl disc; Philips, G03625L. (Audio 8)
    Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Over the hills and far away. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1950 February 7.
    Méhul, Etienne Nicolas, 1763-1817. Jeune Henri. Ouverture. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1953 December.
  - Delius, circa 1952; 1 12" vinyl disc; Philips, GL5690. (Audio 8)
    Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Appalachia (1903). Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Royal Philharmonic Chorus; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. Circa 1952 October - December.
    Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Arabesk. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Royal Philharmonic Chorus; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor.
  - Brahms and Schumann, 1953-1955; 1 12" vinyl disc; EMI, 2905761. (Audio 8)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 Symphonies, no. 3, op. 90, F major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1955 August 16.
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Symphonies, no. 4, op. 120, D minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1953 May 15; 1953 May 21.
  - Brahms, 1932 November 13; 1 12" vinyl disc; EMI, 2909671. (Audio 8)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 40, E♭ major. Busch, Adolf, 1891-1952, violin. Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, horn. Serkin, Rudolf, 1903-1991, piano. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1932 November 13.
  - Brahms, 1956-1957; 1 12" vinyl disc; Columbia, 33CX 1504. (Audio 8)
  - Brahms, 1953 May 22; 1 12" vinyl disc; World Records (EMI), SH314. (Audio 8)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1953 May 22.
  - Britten, circa 1953; 1 12" vinyl disc; London, 5358. (Audio 8)
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Illuminations. Pears, Peter, Sir, tenor. New Symphony Orchestra of London; Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962, conductor.
  - Mozart, 1954 May 19-23; 1 12" vinyl disc; His Masters Voice, XLP30004. (Audio 8)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, K. 452, E♭ major. Horsley, Colin, piano. Dennis Brain Wind Ensemble. 1954 May 19-23.
  - Dennis Brain, horn: in recital, circa 1955; 1 12" vinyl disc; Educational Media Associates, IGI370. (Audio 8)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 270, B♭ major. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet.
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, op. 16, E♭ major. Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976, piano. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. 1955.
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, horn, piano, op. 17, F major. Hansen, Conrad, piano.
    Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974. Cheminée du roi René. Chasse á Valabre. Dennis Brain Wind Quintet. 1955.
  - Harry Blech conducting the London Mozart Players, 1952 December 22; 1 12" vinyl disc; His Masters Voice, CLP1009. Published 1955. (Audio 8)
  - Mozart, 1957 May 16; 1 12" vinyl disc; Precision Records and Tapes, GSGC7056. (Audio 8)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Serenades, K. 388, C minor. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Serenades, K. 375, E♭ major (1782). London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor.
  - Unreleased performances of Dennis Brain, circa 1955-1979; 1 12" vinyl disc; Arabesque Recordings, 8071. Published 1995. (Audio 8)
    Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994 and Morris, Gareth, remember playing with Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, in the RAF Central Band and RAF Symphony Orchestra.
    Morris, Gareth, talks about Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, leading his wind ensemble. Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994 describes how he led the horns in an orchestra. Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994, Morris, Gareth, and Parry, Wilfred, tell stories of Brain's love of driving.
    Aprahamian, Felix, talks about Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, specifically his organ playing ability and his influence as a horn player.
    Lecture Recital - The Early Horn. Excerpt. Neill Sanders. horn. British Broadcasting Corporation. Third Programme. 1955 July 28.
    Morris, Gareth, and Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994, sum up Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, as a person. Parry, Wilfred, pays a final tribute.
  - Hoffnung Music Festival, 1956 November 13; 1 12" vinyl disc; Angel, 35500. (Audio 8)
  - Aubrey Brain: Mozart, Brahms, and Glazunov, 1926-1927; 1 12" vinyl disc; Opal. 805. (Audio 8)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 40, E♭ major. Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, horn. Dyke, Spencer, 1880-1946, violin. Bowen, Edwin York 1884-1961, piano. 1926.
    Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Rêverie. Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, horn. Brain, Marion, piano. 1927.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, horn. Royal Symphony Orchestra; Brain, Batten, Joseph, conductor. 1927.
  - Mozart and Haydn, 1952 April-June; 1 12" vinyl disc; Decca. LXT2753. (Audio 8)
    Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 49, F minor. London Mozart Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1952 Apr 21.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 131, D major. London Mozart Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1952 April 25; 1952 Jun 24.
  - Beethoven, 1954 September-November; 1 12" vinyl disc; Columbia, 33CX1266. (Audio 8)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 67, C minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1954 November 9-10.
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1805). Komm Hoffnung. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Watford Town Hall. 1954 September 20.
  - Rossini overtures, 1953 January 19-21; 1 12" vinyl disc; Music for Pleasure, MFP2031. (Audio 9)
    Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Italiana in Algeri. Overture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 January 19.
    Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Scala di seta. Overture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 January 19.
    Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Guillaume Tell. Ouverture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 January 20.
    Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Semiramide. Overture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 January 21.
    Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Signor Bruschino. Overture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 January 19.
    Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Cenerentola. Overture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 January 19.
  - Cantelli conducts French orchestral masterpieces, 1954-1956; 1 12" vinyl disc; EMI, XLP30092. (Audio 9)
  - 1812 and other famous overtures, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; Music for Pleasure, MFP2034. (Audio 9)
    Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. 1812. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor.
    Hérold, Ferdinand, 1791-1833. Zampa. Ouverture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor.
    Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Hebriden. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor.
    Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Ruy Blas (Overture). Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor.
    Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895. Dichter und Bauer. Ouvertüre. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor.
  - Goldmark, circa 1957; 1 12" vinyl disc; Philips, GL5719. (Audio 9)
    Goldmark, Carl, 1830-1915. Ländliche Hochzeit. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor.
  - Moura Lympany, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; Music for Pleasure, MFP2064. (Audio 9)
    Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 16, A minor. Lympany, Moura, 1916-2005, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Menges, Herbert, 1902-1972, conductor.
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Concertos, piano, orchestra, op. 54, A minor. Lympany, Moura, 1916-2005, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Silvestri, Constantin, 1913-1969, conductor.
    Additional materials
    Includes: a photocopy of the reverse of the sleeve for another recording of Grieg's Concerto in A Minor (Op.16), Columbia 33C1040; and a newspaper clipping for a Moura Lympany recital, dated 1986 September 16.
  - Tchaikovsky and Prokofiev, 1955 February 7-11; 1 12" vinyl disc; Music for Pleasure, MFP2047. (Audio 9)
    Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Nutcracker suite. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1955 February 9; 1955 February 11.
    Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Li︠u︡bovʹ k trem apelʹsinam. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1955 February 7; 1955 February 9.
  - Rachmaninov and Mendelssohn, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; Music for Pleasure, MFP2035. (Audio 9)
    Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 18, C minor. Lympany, Moura, 1916-2005, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor.
    Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Capriccio brillant. Lympany, Moura, 1916-2005, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor.
  - Mozart and Berkeley, circa 1953-1957; 1 12" vinyl disc; Capitol, G7175. Published 1959. (Audio 9)
  - Dennis Brain plays horn concertos, 1956 September-November; 1 12" vinyl disc; His Masters Voice, HLS7001. (Audio 9)
    Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 2, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Sawallisch, Wolfgang, 1923-2013, conductor. 1956 September.
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Concertos, horn, orchestra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963, conductor. 1956 November.
    Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 1, op. 11, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Sawallisch, Wolfgang, 1923-2013, conductor. 1956 September.
  - Dennis Brain: the art of the french horn, 1956-1957; 1 12" vinyl disc; Everest, 3432. (Audio 9)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, horn, violin, violas, cello, K. 407, E♭ major. Carter String Trio. 1956 November 3.
    Marais, Marin, 1656-1728. Pièces de violes, 4e livre. 1ère partie. Suitte, no. 5. Basque. Parry, Wilfrid, piano. Edinburgh International Festival. 1957 August 24. Includes an encore, introduced by Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, a rare recording of the performers voice.
  - Mozart, circa 1950-1957; 1 12" vinyl disc; Columbia, CX1140. (Audio 9)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor.
  - Hindemith, 1956 November; 1 12" vinyl disc; Angel, 35491. (Audio 9)
  - The art of Dennis Brain, 1944-1953; 1 12" vinyl disc; Seraphim, 60040. (Audio 9)
  - The art of Dennis Brain vol.2, circa 1953-1957; 1 12" vinyl disc; Seraphim, 60073. (Audio 9)
  - The art of Dennis Brain vol.3, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; Seraphim, 60169. (Audio 9)
  - Borodin, 1955 September 23-24; 1 12" vinyl disc; His Masters Voice, XLP30010. (Audio 9)
    Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Symphonies, no. 3, A minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1955 September 23.
  - Borodin and Rimsky-Korsakov, circa 1957; 1 12" vinyl disc; Angel, 35346. (Audio 9)
    Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Symphonies, no. 1, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor.
    Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Ispanskoe kaprichchio. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor.
  - Bach, 1952 October-November; 2 12" vinyl discs; EMI, 2909743. (Audio 9)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Masses, BWV 232, B minor. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Höffgen, Marga, contralto. Gedda, Nicolai, tenor. Rehfuss, Heinz, bass. Parikian, Manoug, violin. Morris, Gareth, flute. Sutcliffe, Sidney, oboe d'amore. Newbury, Peter, oboe d'amore. ones, Geraint, 1917-1998, organ. Gesellschaft der Musikfreunde in Wien; Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1952 October 26; 1952 November 5.
  - Wagner, circa 1948; 1 12" vinyl disc; Seraphim, 60003. (Audio 9)
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Siegfrieds Rheinfahrt. Wiener Philharmoniker; Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954, conductor.
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Brünnhildes Schlussgesang. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954, conductor.
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Trauermarsch. Wiener Philharmoniker; Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954, conductor. 1948 March 26.
  - Kodaly and Dohnanyi, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; Music For Pleasure, MFP2042. (Audio 9)
    Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967. Háry János. Suite. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Schüchter, Wilhelm, conductor.
    Dohnányi, Christoph von. Ruralia Hungarica Suite. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Schüchter, Wilhelm, conductor.
  - Tchaikovsky, 1954 January - February; 1 12" vinyl disc; His Masters Voice, XLP30015. (Audio 9)
  - Mendelssohn, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; His Masters Voice, XLP30025. (Audio 9)
    Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Sommernachtstraum. Selections. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki, Paul, conductor.
  - Tchaikovsky, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; His Masters Voice, ALP1491. (Audio 9)
    Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Silvestri, Constantin, 1913-1969, conductor.
  - Beethoven, undated; 1 12" vinyl disc; Columbia, RL3035. (Audio 9)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Symphonies, no. 7, op. 92, A major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor.
  - Rossini-Respighi and Dukas, circa 1953; 1 12" vinyl disc; World Sound, T582. (Audio 9)
    Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Boutique fantasque. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 April 11-15.
    Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Apprenti sorcier. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor.
  - Mozart, 1950 June; 1 12" vinyl disc; Turnabout, THS65046. (Audio 9)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, piano, orchestra, K. 466, D minor. Schnabel, Artur, 1882-1951, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1950 June.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, piano, orchestra, K. 491, C minor. Schnabel, Artur, 1882-1951, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1950 June.
  - Dinu Lipatti plays the Grieg and Schumann piano concertos, 1947-1948; 1 12" vinyl disc; His Masters Voice, XLP30072. (Audio 9)
    Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 16, A minor. Lipatti, Dinu, 1917-1950, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor, conductor. 1947 September 18-19.
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Concertos, piano, orchestra, op. 54, A minor. Lipatti, Dinu, 1917-1950, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1948 April 9-10.
  - Solomon plays Grieg and Schumann piano concertos, 1956 September; 1 12" vinyl disc; Classics for pleasure, CFP40255. (Audio 9)
    Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Concerto, piano, orchestra, op. 16, A minor. Solomon, 1902-1988, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Menges, Herbert, 1902-1972, conductor. 1956 September 25-26.
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Concertos, piano, orchestra, op. 54, A minor. Solomon, 1902-1988, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Menges, Herbert, 1902-1972, conductor. 1956 September 18-19; 1956 September 24.
  - Solomon - Beethoven, 1952 November 2; 1 10" vinyl discs; His Masters Voice, BLP1024. (Audio 9)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 19, B♭ major. Solomon, 1902-1988, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cluytens, André, conductor. 1952 November 2.
  - Strauss, 1953 September; 1 12" vinyl disc; Angel, 38266. Published 1985. (Audio 9)
  - Mozart: Cosi fan tutte, 1954 July-November; 3 12" vinyl discs; WRC, SOC195/6/7. (Audio 9)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Così fan tutte. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Merriman, Nan, mezzo-soprano. Otto, Lisa, soprano. Simoneau, Léopold, tenor. Panerai, Rolando, baritone. Bruscantini, Sesto, baritone. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England), Philharmonia Chorus (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1954 July 13-21; 1954 November 6.
  - Wagner: Tristan and Isolde, 1952 October 22; 4 12" vinyl discs; Seraphim, ID16147. (Audio 9)
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. Suthaus, Ludwig, tenor. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano. Thebom, Blanche, mezzo-soprano. Greindl, Josef, bass. Fischer-Dieskau, Dietrich, 1925-2012, baritone. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1886-1954, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1952 October 22.
- Video, circa 1941-1955; 16 items 1 CD-R; 2 DVD-Rs; 5 DVDs; 8 videocassettes
  Dennis Brain's involvement in these performances is assumed and therefore his name is not stated in the performance listings unless his involvement was other than that of hornist.
  - British Pathe film of the 1955 Edinburgh Festival, 1954 September 1; 1 CD-R 1 video file; Windows media (Box 2, Disc 171)
    British Pathé News film of the 1955 Edinburgh Festival. Published in 1955 but filmed 1954 September 1. Simm, Alistair, narrator. Includes a rehearsal at Usher Hall during which Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, performs, Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. 2. Aufzug. 2. Szenen. Mässig bewegt. Filming was conducted prior to a concert with the Norddeutscher Rundfunk. Sinfonie-Orchester; Schmidt-Isserstedt, Hans, 1900-1973, conductor. This film is one of only two known video recordings of Dennis Brain which demonstrates his stature and embouchure.
  - Magic Canvas, The, 1948; 2 DVD-Rs 2 copies (Box 6, Box 2, Disc 301)
    Soundtrack credits
    Seiber, Mátyás, 1905-1960. Phantasies, flute, horn, strings. Blech String Quartet. Morris, Gareth, flute. Background music for The Magic Canvas (1948), a short animated film directed by Halas, John.
  - Treasure Island, 1950; 1 DVD; Disney DVD, 30157. (Box 6)
    Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Mathieson, Muir, conductor. Parker, Clifton, composer.
    Technical specification
    NTSC. Region 1.
  - War classics: Target for tonight, 1941; 1 DVD; Echo Bridge Home Entertainment, 28479. Published 2004. (Box 6)
    Central Band of the Royal Air Force (Great Britain); Hollingsworth, John, 1916-1963, conductor. Lucas, Leighton, 1903-1982, composer. 1941.
  - Happy and glorious, 1953; 1 DVD; Yesteryear, GLDVD/Y01. Published 2007. (Box 6)
    Original newsreel footage of the coronation of Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1926-. The coronation service featured an ad hoc orchestra consisting of players drawn from leading London orchestras. Westminster Abbey. 1953 June 2.
    Technical specifications
    PAL. Region 0.
  - Scott of the Antarctic, 1948; 1 DVD; 905 Entertainment, 3463. Published 2005. (Box 6)
    Irving, Ernest, 1878-1953, conductor. Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958, composer.
  - Overlanders, The, 1946; 1 DVD; Hollywood's Attic, 2005D. Published 2009. (Box 6)
    Irving, Ernest, 1878-1953, conductor. Ireland, John, 1879-1962, composer.
  - Red shoes, The; Oliver Twist, 1948; 1 videocassette (Box 7)
    The Red Shoes. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. Easdale, Brian, 1909-1995, composer.
    Oliver Twist. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Mathieson, Muir, conductor. Bax, Arnold, 1883-1953, composer.
  - Dennis Brain: Beethoven horn sonata Op.17, 1952; 1 videocassette; Amati Video (Box 7)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, horn, piano, op. 17, F major. Matthews, Denis, piano. 1952.
    NTSC
  - Captain from Castile, 1947; 1 videocassette (Box 7)
    Newman, Alfred, 1901-1970, composer.
  - Cruel sea, The, 1953; 1 videocassette; Lumiere Pictures / Republic Pictures. VHS5828. Published 1993. (Box 7)
    Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Irving, Ernest, 1878-1953, conductor. Rawsthorne, Alan, 1905-1971, composer. 1953.
  - Dennis Brain at the Edinburgh Festival, 1955; 1 videocassette (Box 7)
  - London's country: yesterday's Britain No.24, 1948-1954; 2 videocassettes 2 copies; Fame, YB24. Published 1997. (Box 7)
    London's Country (1954); Open House (1951); Country Buses (1948). The three films on this video were made for London Transport over a five year period when Britain was recovering from the war and enjoying new opportunities heralded with the Festival of Britain (1951).
    Copies note
    The original published copy appears to be defective. A second duplicate copy has therefore been retained.
  - Science in the orchestra: Dennis Brain?, undated; 1 videocassette (Audio 7)